Email: teresa_kropp@yahoo.com Home#: (818) 887-4904 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/teresahkropp

Dear Sir or Madam,

In the interest of pursuing a position with your organization, I have enclosed my resume for your review and consideration.

I have a strong background in software development, software applications and testing, database and network management, Agile methodology, and internal liaison/training work. My personal strengths are in engineering/testing, leading/managing a team of engineers, and communications. As we both know, these skills are an unusual combination. I have worked as a software developer, technical support engineer, software instructor, QA manager, and as a software quality assurance engineer over the past years. I have many years of experience working at start-up companies.

I offer:

- Strong analytical and problem solving skills with a solid reputation for root cause analysis, essential for managing multiple projects effectively.
- Exceptional follow-through abilities, a take charge professional who sees projects to successful completion on time and consistently exceeding specifications.
- Excellent ability to interact effectively with people at all levels of operations, of diverse cultural backgrounds, personalities, and temperaments. Able to build rapport and establish solid relationships with customers, management, and all levels of staff(technical and non-technical people).

Highlights of my career include:

- <u>ACR Systems:</u> Worked with Tandy to replace their Point-of-Sales software at 5,200 Radio Shack stores in the U.S.
- <u>Legato Systems:</u> Worked at a small, start-up company that surpassed its major competitors(Palindrome and Cheyenne ARCserve) in sales, going IPO, and being bought out by EMC.

I look forward to speaking with you personally so that we may discuss how I can fulfill the specific needs of your company.

Sincerely,

Teresa H. Kropp

Email: teresa kropp@yahoo.com Home#: (818) 887-4904

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/teresahkropp

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Networks: LAN, WAN, TCP/IP, VLANs, SNMP, ATM, and other Layer 2

and 3 network protocols

Languages: C++, C#, ADA, JAVA, XML, PYTHON

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, Firebase,

MongoDB, Local Storage, Node.js, React.js, Handlebars.js,

Express, Github, Heroku, Responsive Design, User

Authentication(Passport), APIs, Slack

Operating Systems: UNIX(HP-UX, Sun Solaris, IBM AIX), Linux, Windows, Mac OS

Databases: Oracle, Sybase(SAP), IBM Informix, MS Access, Siebel Problem

Reporting System, IBM Rational ClearCase/ClearQuest, MySQL, MS SQL Server, MAPICS (Database query tools: HeidiSQL,

Toad)

Automated Testing

Tools: Simple Tester, Mercury Interactive WinRunner and TestDirector,

Mercury Interactive QuickTest Professional(QTP), Selenium

Network Traffic

Testing Tools: NetXRay, SmartBits, InfoVista, MIMIC SNMP Simulator

Revision Control Management/Project or Test Management/

Continuous Integration Tools: Perforce, Apache Subversion, GIT, Jenkins,

CruiseControl, Sourcegear Vault Standard,

Testrail, Redmine, HP Quality Center, Jira, Mingle

Microsoft

Applications: Excel, OutLook, Word, PowerPoint, Project, Visual Studio(.NET

Framework), SharePoint

Other: Enterprise Architect, WinSCP, PuTTY, JBoss Application Server,

Apache Tomcat Web Server, Apache Maven Build Automation

Tool for Java, Fiddler(web debugging tool)

Email: teresa kropp@yahoo.com Home#: (818) 887-4904

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/teresahkropp

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Coding Bootcamp @ UCLA Extension, Woodland Hills, CA Full-Stack Web Developer (July 2017 to Present)

- Created several web apps that are visually appealing, as well as organized and functional.
- Skills include: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Handlebars.js, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Github, Heroku, Responsive Design, User Authentication(Passport), APIs, Slack
- Group Project EventStay: https://thkropp1.github.io/EventStay/
- GitHub Projects: https://github.com/thkropp1

FilmTrack, Studio City, CA

QA Engineer (May 2015 to January 2016)

- Wrote test cases based on user stories and/or software defect tickets from Jira. Added the testcases to Testrail.
- Participated in daily SCRUM meetings and reported my test results.
- Worked closely with product management, and also with development teams and customer support, in order to test new features, as well as bug fixes from Jira.
- Helped with Selenium Automation(written in C# and Javascript).
- Wrote How-To documents about the Avails Contracts and Rights Management software for Media and Entertainment companies such as Dreamworks and Miramax.

Tradescape, Encino, CA

QA Lead (October 2013 to June 2014)

- Wrote test cases and executed them for Global Clearing House(GCH), used by Universal Music Group. Areas: User Data Access Management(Permissions), Suspense Management(including Automatic), Allocations, Participation, and Business Partner Contracts(BPP). GCH is a billing and settlement system for Digital Media Value Chains, such as for YouTube and Apple iTunes.
- Worked closely with product and project management, and also with development teams, in order to create release/milestone plans, provide testing estimates, and report testing status.
- Wrote test plans and test cases based on software functional specifications, business rules/requirements, and use cases.

Email: teresa_kropp@yahoo.com Home#: (818) 887-4904 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/teresahkropp

• Worked together with developers to refine tests and proactively identify and document the defects in HP Quality Center(QC), and assisted in the resolution of defects by use of grey-box testing techniques(MySQL queries) and regression testing before the software was released to the client.

• Handled multiple projects simultaneously, with some having the same deadlines.

Entertainment Partners, Burbank, CA

Sr. QA Engineer (February 2010 to October 2013)

- Wrote test cases and tested Vista5, a production accounting software. Areas: Accounts Payable, Payments, General Ledger, Payroll, Budget, Petty Cash, Pcard.
- Created and deployed QA builds to JBoss Application servers, and set up databases in MS SQL Server 2008. Wrote batch scripts to improve the build process.
- Created build deployment packages for UAT and for Production.
- Created "How To" documents for QA software processes.
- Created a standardized test case template for QA.
- Performed smoke test and regression test analysis for writing QTP automation test cases.
- Verified software defect fixes, and wrote up test results and test plans, and logged software defects into IBM Rational ClearQuest and into Mingle.
- Worked in production support extensively with the product manager/business owner, development manager, project manager, business analysts, developers, and other product support engineers to resolve client issues.
- Participated in software requirements reviews and project planning.
- Trained QA engineers(on-site and off-shore).
- Wrote about 1000 test cases, 306 software defect reports, and tested 352 software requirements in one year.
- Clients include: NBC, Indie, LionsGate, Sony, CBS

SmartEquip, Agoura Hills, CA

QA Manager (April 2006 to January 2009)

- Managed day-to-day tasks and schedules of the entire company's software QA department. Built the company's entire QA department from scratch.
- Helped mature the company's development/QA processes by establishing a "Methodology of Testing Bug Fixes Guideline" document for the developers and OA to follow.
- Managed 21 projects through MS SharePoint with 8-10 projects active concurrently(with similar deadlines).

Email: teresa_kropp@yahoo.com Home#: (818) 887-4904

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/teresahkropp

• Cross-trained and mentored staff by increasing their knowledge and skills, in order to improve team performance and to mitigate the risk of an indispensable engineer.

- Directed developers to fix the broken refactored software the day before it was presented to a major potential client, United Rentals(they ended up signing the contract with SmartEquip), when the Development Manager and VP of Engineering were unable to be contacted.
- Developed and implemented comprehensive test plans(where none existed before) with test cases from the Census bug-tracking database and from Change Requests(Requirements)/Technical Specifications for functional and regression testing. Developed and implemented test matrices to track the quality of the software features and to identify the high-risk problem areas in the software. Wrote up 389 test cases in a year's time.
- Performed functional and regression testing from the end user's perspective, as well as led the test efforts on the graphical, web-based software application(written in Flash, XML, JAVA/JAVASCRIPT, and MySQL), verified fixed bugs, and opened new bug issues to track the software defects through their lifecycle. Wrote up 244 defects in a year's time. Used Fiddler and Charles to log the input and output of data on Apache Tomcat Web servers to and from the various manufacturers' parts inventory databases like SAP or MAPICS.
- Tested deployed pre-production(client acceptance) and post-production software releases, whether the releases were scheduled or unscheduled.
- Coordinated project meetings, generated meeting minutes and status reports for management on a regular basis, and tracked the open/fixed bug issues, as well as the quality of the software features.
- Participated in product requirement and technical specifications reviews.
- Interfaced with developers in duplicating problems, isolating causes(detecting and analyzing software defects), and verifying bug fixes.
- Assisted technical support in resolving customers' issues.
- Dedicated to ensuring that the software delivered to the customers adhered to their requirements and were of high quality.
- Familiar with SDLC and established best QA practices, where none existed before.
- JLG, one of SmartEquip's biggest customers, declared that the R2 release of SmartEquip's software was the best in terms of quality that they have seen in years after I've been with the company for 4 months.
- Other customers: Caterpillar, Sunbelt, John Deere, MultiQuip, Genie.

Email: teresa kropp@yahoo.com Home#: (818) 887-4904

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/teresahkropp

Alcatel, Calabasas, CA

Senior Unit Test Engineer and Technical Lead (February 2000 to March 2006)

- Project lead for a group of testers for Alcatel's OmniSwitches 7700 and 7800(SNMP Agent and MIBs), OmniVista, and WebView. QA Manager for 5 months for this group, as well as a full-time tester on two projects(OmniVista and WebView) simultaneously.
- Met ALL schedule deadlines for X-Vision, SNMP, OmniVista, and WebView projects assigned at the same time.
- Adhered to guidelines and standards for ISO 9001 and CMM compliance.
- Experienced in automated testing tools such as WinRunner/Test Director,
 QuickTest Pro, and SimpleTester and network traffic generating tools such as NetXRay and SmartBits.
- Initiated automating WebView(Web Browser based software) test cases using QuickTest Pro.
- Functional, regression, stress, load, and performance testing X-Vision, OmniVista, and WebView, three Enterprise Network Management Systems designed to manage and configure the OmniStack, OmniSwitch and OmniS/R families of multi-layer switching products from Alcatel, as well as from other switch vendors.
- Worked on a project testing SNMP Agent and MIBs. Used MIMIC SNMP Simulator to simulate SNMP-manageable devices on a PC and to compile SMI-compliant MIBs.
- Coordinated project meetings and generate meeting minutes and status reports for management on a regular basis, using the Siebel Problem Reporting System, Oracle Discoverer 3.1 User Edition, and Excel spreadsheets.
- Installed client-server network management software and configuring network testbed environments on OS platforms: Windows, HP-UX, Sun Solaris, IBM AIX, and Linux.

OTHER WORK HISTORY

ACR Systems, Inc., Woodland Hills, CA Senior Quality Assurance Analyst

• Worked with Tandy's QA department in replacing their proprietary POS(Point-of-Sale) software for 5,200 Radio Shack stores across the United States.

Email: teresa kropp@yahoo.com Home#: (818) 887-4904

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/teresahkropp

One Step Data, Inc., Glendale, CA

Technical Support Engineer

Certified RetailPro Technician. RetailPro is a POS software for retail stores.

Bonafide Management Systems, Thousand Oaks, CA

Technical Support/Systems Analyst

• Set up entire PC Point-of-Sale systems for retail stores, which involved installing and configuring the operating systems, loading and configuring the company software, and preparing instructions for use of the system and software.

IntelligenceWare, Inc., Los Angeles, CA

Technical Support/Systems Analyst

- Customized database mining applications for customers, and worked at customer sites to resolve clients' issues.
- Represented company at National Trade Shows.

Legato Systems(now EMC), Mountain View, CA

Technical Support Engineer

- Assisted technical reviewers to prepare evaluations of Networker products for both <u>Info World</u> and <u>Open Systems Today</u> publications. As a result, Legato Systems scored the highest from both publications in the technical support area against its two competitors, and sales of Legato Systems software increased.
- Recognized for promptly answering and resolving 50% more calls than average.

Trifox, Inc., Campbell, CA

Software Engineer, Technical Support and Applications

- Wrote customized database applications for clients: NASA Kennedy Space Center, Conrail RailRoad.
- Developed instructional materials and traveled extensively on the East Coast to conduct seminars on the proper use and maintenance of the company's software for Trifox customers.

Email: teresa kropp@yahoo.com Home#: (818) 887-4904

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/teresahkropp

GTE Government Systems(now Verizon), Mountain View, CA **Software Engineer**

Top Secret Security Clearance: Department of Defense (SBI-SCI access)

- Designed software interfaces between subsystems for a radar tracking system on a Hughes aircraft.
- Developed software for diagnostics testing on several subsystems.
- Rewrote object oriented design programs.
- Designed and implemented training seminars.
- Created, maintained, and supported Configurations Management software tools.

EDUCATION

Member of Toastmasters International: CC, ACB, CL, ALB designations

2017 Full Stack Web Development Certification(UCLA Extension)

2014 Java Programming Certification(University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign)

2010 Production Accounting for Film and Television(UCLA Extension)

2005 Alcatel Certified Switch Expert(Alcatel-Lucent)

2001 Certification in Web Development and Administration(Learning Tree University)

University of California at Berkeley, College of Engineering

Bachelor of Science – Engineering Science/Mathematics

Completed courses in EECS(Electrical Engineering Computer Science).

Achievements: Cal Alumni Scholar